trading is already hard enough and
imagine only having a small window of 5
to 6 hours or even just a couple of
minutes and this is usually not doable
for a lot of people because they work
jobs and the different time zones that
the market is available in those small
window periods and that's exactly where
swing trading falls into place everybody
can do it it doesn't matter if you work
at 9 to5 if you work during the day if
you work during the night if you're a
swing Trader you can basically trade
whenever ever you want and actually you
can make a lot more money as a swing
Trader compared to a day trader or a
scout Trader with the things that I'm
going to share with you in this video so
make sure you watch all the way to the
end so you're probably wondering what is
a swing Trader well the basis of it is a
Trader that holds a position for more
than 7 days and usually closes their
position at about two to 3 weeks Max so
a swing Trader is when you swing a
position throughout the weekend and you
hold into the other weekend anything
under 7 days or under a position that
you hold throughout the weekend is
considered a intraday or a day trader so
swing Traders are your in positions for
7 days and above up to about 2 to 3
weeks a day trader is somebody that's in
the position just for the day so for 5
to 6 to seven hours and then a scalp
Trader is somebody that's in a position
very fast can be 15 minutes 1 Hour 2
hours and that's a lot for a scalper so
this is a very simple and Broad ter
terminology of what is an actual swing
Trader but the swing Trader actually
earns his title by the way he analyzes
the market and that is by analyzing the
markets on the higher time frames so
what makes a swing Trader a swing Trader
well the first things first is that
you're only looking to take maybe one to
two positions a week Max because as a
swing Trader you're taking the best
quality trades that can play out in the
following week or two so if you're
looking for a position to play out in
the next week or two you usually have to
be more patient and they don't come
around every single day and sometimes
even for weeks so you're taking around
one to two trades a week Max and you're
going to only be focusing on the markets
that are low volume markets you don't
want to be involved in markets that have
a move within the day or within the hour
you're looking to catch a big move in
the market where you can hold it for
about 7 to 8 to 9 days this way you can
maximize your profits and this is good
because if you work a 9 to5 or you're
just busy with your life this lets the
trade give you a plenty of running space
and also availability for you to enter
the trade whenever you have free time so
you don't actively have to be watching
the market every single day so as a
swing Trader you're focusing on the
markets that move the slowest but
respect the market structure the most
and respect the strategy the most simply
because they move slower and it's good
because in the markets patience pays and
the swing Traders are the most patient
Traders that's why they make the most
money and they make the most money not
only because they're actually catching
one of the biggest moves in the market
that a day trader or a scalp Trader can
never catch they're actually risking
more than a day trader and a scalper
simply because they're taking less
amount of Trades and the less amount of
Trades that you take the higher quality
of the trade that it actually is so here
you would be risking a higher percentage
that you normally would on a day trade
or a scout trade so the higher risk you
take on a trade with a bigger move that
you would be taking pretty much means
you're going to make more money and what
really makes a swing Trader a swing
Trader is that they spend no time in
front of the charts compared to a day
trader or compared to a scoer you
realistically only have to be in front
of the markets maybe one to 3 hours a
week because once you're in a position
you simply set and forget you don't have
to monitor the position every single day
every single hour every single session
you just execute the trade wait for it
to take profit or you wait for it to hit
your stop- loss and that is as soon as
you enter the trade because as soon as
you enter it you don't look at it until
it hits either or but before you enter
it you can just check in pretty much
every session once a day or twice a day
but you don't actively have to be in
front of the computer every single day
at a specific session for a specific
amount of time as soon as you enter the
trade literally set and forget and most
importantly it's most appealing to the
majority of the people because everybody
can do it you can work a 9 to 5 a 7 to3
any different time zone that you work
you can be a swing Trader because you
can trade the market at any session and
you can simply hold the trade for 5 to
six days where if you were to be busy at
work you don't have to be paying
attention to the market because your
trade is simply just running into profit
or running into stop l so I'm going to
lay out some pretty simple and obvious
pros and cons so obviously the first pro
is that literally anybody can do this
you can be working a job you can be
going to school fulltime or you can be
retired and you can actively become a
swing Trader because it's almost good
that you're busy with a job or busy at
school because you can simply only
dedicate the time that you need to to
the markets and then you go put your
focus on something else makes you
actually be more patient in the market
which is actually in turn going to give
you better results because you're taking
better quality trades so a good Pro
realistically is that it is available
for absolutely everybody but that
actually comes with a con where it's a
double-edged sword and it's if you have
too much free time
that you can become impatient because
you simply have nothing else to do so
you're a retired person and you simply
want to get involved into the markets if
you're doing nothing all day you're
going to be more prone to look at the
markets than somebody that's going to
school or has a job so you might be
finding taking more positions and you
might think that taking more positions
is going to make you more money and
that's not how it works so a con is that
if you have no patience this is not the
right position for you and simply will
not work work out second is you're more
likely to succeed than any other
different type of Market approach more
than a scalper and more than a day
trader why well simply because the rule
of less is more in trading and a swing
Trader does less and makes more they
only take one to two positions and they
make more money and catch bigger moves
than day traded to scers where they're
taking three to four to five to six
positions a week but Simply Having less
results because they're executing more
picture a swing Trader as a sniper a
sniper simply sitting at the back of a
hill waiting for its Target to get in
place and they soon as they take the
shot they're 100% sure that they're
going to execute on that shot and
picture a day and a scalper as somebody
with a pistol or even a bow and arrow
that you can simply shoot it a bunch of
times and hopefully get lucky and hit
one time so a sniper also known as a
swing Trader is somebody that executes
the perfect trade and they rarely ever
Miss so your Odo succeeding with a swing
trading approach is more likely than a
day trading or scalping approach the
approach of you shooting a target with a
sniper you're going to be a lot more
accurate than shooting it with a pistol
or a bow and arrow a con with that
though might come that you don't know
who you are just yet because I didn't
know I was going to be an extremely
successful swing trade at the beginning
I wanted to be a day trader day trader
is the main topic that everybody sees on
social media and it's what's been
normalized in the industry so a con is
that you can come in thinking that you
want to be a day trader and then you end
up a scalper and you want to be a
scalper and you end up a swing Trader so
you kind of have to find yourself in
this journey of a Trader and that can
honestly take some time but that off
becomes to you and the amount of
dedication that you put into this
never-ending craft and obviously one of
the biggest Pros is that you can make a
lot more money than day trading and
scalping because you're simply getting
bigger positions you're catching a trade
that that will run for 5 6 7 8 9 10 days
one position opposed to day traded
scalpers that they'll have one position
run for 1 to two to 3 to 4 hours so they
can only maximize their profits within
how much that they makes if you hold a
position for a week you're catching a
whole week of a Market's move that one
simple day can never outdo a whole week
of a market move so you can actually
make a lot more money but that comes
with a con as well that you can
obviously risk more money and you can
lose more money but risk reward ratio
and all of that will outweigh and you're
going to become profitable at the end of
the day you can picture the big profits
that you would make in swing trading as
if you were to be deep sea fishing so
you obviously have to wait a lot more
time for your bait to reach all the way
to the bottom and you have to wait a lot
more time for this big ginormous fish to
eat the bait and it's going to cost you
a lot more money to go out there into
the deep ocean and pay for this
expensive big bait so this ginormous
fish can then eat it and then it's going
to take you some time to then reel that
big fish up hopefully the lines not snap
but at the end of the day once you get
the fish on board all of it is worth it
compared if you were to just get a
little boat go out to very shallow
Waters use a very simple Rod very simple
bait you can get a lot of little fish
but it'll never compare to one big fish
that you can simply get by just one
simple cast compared to you having to
cast out 100 times to potentially equal
the same size of one big fish that you
would get as a deep sea Fisher and that
actually just reminds me that I
literally just made
$363,000 I think in the last position
that I took and I did not take a
position for nearly 2 weeks in order to
catch this one trade because the market
simply wasn't giving me a good trade
opportunity so I waited for that great
opportunity and I risked more and
clearly it paid out was my biggest trade
where I made 3
$63,000 and had just broken my new
record so this is a perfect example
comparing to the fishing I would much
rather catch a big fish at the Ocean
than catching a bunch of little fish
right by the shore and if you want to
see that video on how I made
$360,000 in one single trade make sure
you click this video up here I'm going
to break down exactly on how I did it so
you can see if you can replicate the
same exact trade and also catch a trade
just like that all right actually it's
here and the Subscribe button is here so
if you have not subscribed hit the
Subscribe button it's on one of these
two sides hit the Subscribe button now
so now after you've hit the Subscribe
button please make sure you have hit it
I'm going to actually show you how you
can actually become a swing Trader and
we're going to go ahead now to the
charts and I'm going to show you exactly
how to analyze the markets of the Swing
Trader and how I have been personally
doing it for the last seven six and a
half years of trading in these markets
so let me show you guys okay so first
things first that I want to cover is
going to be top down analysis remember
the first thing that makes a Trader a
swing Trader is going to be the analysis
on the time frames that they do it so we
have to start from the top down so we
will be starting from the monthly time
frame so you guys can see up here to the
top left corner I have currently a star
on all the time frames that I use as a
active swing Trader in the markets so as
you can see I have a star on the one
month one week one day the 4 Hour the 2
hour the 1 hour the 30 minute and the 15
minute so I do not use use any other
time frame outside of these time frames
these are the only ones that I focus on
in order to be a successful day trader
in the markets now there is many
different time frames and there is many
different ways on how to look at the
market but this is what I have been
using and it is what works same way how
there is a hundred different types of
boats out there and a 100 different
types of rods in order for you to go out
there and fish in deep sea this is what
works for me and it's what I will be
teaching you today so after you
understand all of these time frames you
would have to do a top down analysis so
top down is very self-explanatory you're
going to start from the top which will
be the highest time frame which is going
to be the monthly and then you would
work your way down to the weekly time
frame then you would work your way down
to the Daily 4 Hour 2 Hour 1 hour 30
minute and 15 minute so everything
you're doing here is You're simply just
zooming in into this Candlestick every
single time as a right now every single
one of these candlesticks are going to
be one week this Candlestick as of right
now has 1 day and 14 hours left because
we're right by the ending of the week if
you were to look at the monthly time
frame the monthly has about 15 days left
in order for this candles stick to close
the daily has about 17 hours in order
for this candles stick to close so on
and so forth so every single time frame
represents what each one of these
candlesticks is Val valued at so each
one of these candlesticks is currently
valued at one day so this is 1 Day 2
days 3 days 4 days 5 days 6 days I head
over to the 4 Hour each one of these
candlesticks is going to be valued at 4
hours as you can see right here this
Candlestick has about an hour 20 left in
order for it to close so when you do a
top down analysis you're going to start
from the highest time frame so this is
where I would then go into the next step
which is going to be the trend so top 10
analysis and understanding the trend of
the market kind of go together but a lot
of Traders get this wrong because they
don't understand that you have to
identify the trend in order you have to
go from the top down you can't just go
from the 4 Hour to then the 1 hour to
then the daily to then the monthly
you're all over the place doesn't make
sense you have to start from the top
down in order for you to understand the
trend of the market so this is where we
would start off on the time frame we
would identify why this time frame has
bearish simply because this Market is
creating lower lows and lower highs and
this Market is clearly heading to the
downside overall then we would go to the
weekly time frame and in the weekly time
frame we can clearly see that this
Market is currently bullish now this is
a very tricky one to tell I can tell
right off the bat because I'm an
experienced Trader I've been doing this
for seven years already but any rookie
or beginner Trader can easily mistake
this for a market that is heading to the
downside and this right here is a
bullish Market because as of right now
this is the higher high point so it
might look like it's overall going down
which you're kind of right but the
actual structure of that point is
bullish so picture it as if the ocean's
current might look like it's going west
but the internal waves are going east
this this is simply because the Winds of
the overall ocean are pushing it that
way but the the ocean has to move with a
current and that current coming back in
is what this weekly time frame is and
it's more of the zoomed in version of
the market so this currently right now
is bullish so you have the monthly time
frame bearish and then you have the
weekly time frame bullish we head over
to the Daily time frame you can also
clearly tell that the daily time frame
is bullish this Market structure is
heading to the upside this is the lower
high lower low and then here we have
just recently shifted to the upside so
this market right here is currently
bullish making now the weekly and the
daily time frame both bullish so as of
right now it's make it more sense to buy
than to sell but we keep it going we go
over to the 4our and on the 4 Hour you
can clearly tell that the 4H hour is
bullish as well well the 4 Hour is
clearly heading to the upside so we're
creating higher highs and higher lows
making this 4-Hour time frame bullish so
think about it for a second you have the
monthly time frame bearish but then you
have the weekly bullish daily bullish
and the 4-Hour bullish I think it makes
more sense to buy than to sell so that's
exactly what we would be doing with the
top down analysis identifying the trend
we want to understand what is the the
market doing overall but after you
understand what the market is doing
overall you have to find an area on
where to buy because you can't just buy
in the middle of anywhere it's like you
just can't drive out into the middle of
the ocean and just park your boat
wherever you want and just throw a bait
thinking that there's going to be fish
there yeah the ocean is huge and yes
there's many fish out there but if you
want to get a really good fish you have
to go to a shipwreck you have to go
where there's caves where there's
certain spots I don't know I'm not a
fisherman so I have no [__] idea but
you have to go to the spot where the
fish are so it's the same thing here you
have to enter the trade where the
trade's going to move at you can't just
enter at any point that's just not how
it works you can't just go fish at any
spot that's just not how it works now
you can catch a fish but it's not the
big one now you can catch a trade
outside of a spot but it's just not the
good one so this is what area of
Interest comes into so you want to enter
a trade at an area of interest and then
this is can be identified as a spot and
also known as support and resistance
which is where you can take a trade to
buy as support or you can sell a trade
to sell as resistance if you're looking
to buy a trade you want to make sure
that you have a support level picture
support as this table right here so I am
using this table as support to push
myself to the upside the same thing that
the market does the market uses a level
of support for example like this one
right here to push itself to the upside
the market came into this area used it
as support three times and it clearly
had a push to the upside because of this
support area now a support level can
also be a resistance level support and
resistance is vice versa same way how I
use this table to push myself up I can
use this table and pull myself down if I
want to use it as a resistance
resistance is like a roof it'll push
yourself down so you can identify a
resistance level as this spot right here
you can see how the market used this
spot as resistance and then it pushed
the market to the downside and then you
can see how it used the same resistance
level as then support because you could
use the same level of support to push
yourself to the upside as then
resistance to pull yourself to the
downside this area is also known as area
of interest it's an area of interest
because whenever you're above it use it
as support whenever you're under it use
it as resistance this is how you would
want to spot an area that you would want
to enter a trade to then execute it with
overall time frames heading in your
favor versus the other side so after you
have this area of Interest or support
eror resistance level it's literally the
same thing oh by the way don't let these
people trick you into this new supply
and demand zone or this order block all
that [__] is [__] I'm telling you
right now I've been in the market for
long enough that I would know if
something new comes into the market and
it's literally they got tired of people
selling support and resistance courses
and then they just came up with you know
what [__] it let's just rename it to
then supplying the man or let's rename
it into order blocks it's the same [__]
at the end of the day nothing changes
supply and demand is literally a
different word for support and
resistance they have both the same exact
effect but do not have anybody out there
trick you into they have the secret way
on how to spot supply and demand or the
secret way on how to oh that's [__]
since trust me I'm saving you guys a
time and I will literally make a video
of order blocks supplying demand or
whatever word they want to call it just
to show you guys that it's literally the
same [__] so stay tuned to that because
it's I'm tired of these people
explaining these [__] videos that
make literally no sense so after you
have your area of Interest supplying
demand whatever the [__] you want to
call it then you have to have your entry
signal which is going to be the reason
why you're going to enter the trade so
same exact thing as you're going to be
fishing after you throw your Rod a fish
has to have a reason why to enter your
bait so you have to have a nice juicy
bait in order they're not not they're
not going to bite the hook they're not
going to put it on themselves so you
need to have a good entry signal in
order to execute this trade and the
entry signal is the last point in the
actual trading plan to execute it
there's other things that have to go
after you execute where I'm going to
explain just in a second so the entry
signal happens after the top down
analysis happens after the trend happens
after the area of Interest then you have
the entry signal a lot of people when
they come into Trading they just focused
on the entry signal at first and dude
that is literally the last thing in
order for you to enter the trade so the
entry signal that you would be looking
for is going to be an engulfing
Candlestick engulfing means when
something eats something when something
is bigger than something so here's where
we would look for an engulfing
Candlestick so if you're looking to buy
a position you want to make sure that
you have a bullish engulfing Candlestick
so picture this as a red candle and then
picture this as a blue candle what is
this candle doing right here it is
engulfing this candle and it is now
going to head to the upside and if
you're looking to sell you need to have
a bearish engulfing Candlestick so you
would have a blue candle and then you
would have a big red Candlestick which
is then going to confirm this position
is going to be heading to the downside
so you have a bullish engulfing
Candlestick and a bearish engulfing
Candlestick very simp simple very
straight to the point it's one
Candlestick that eats the last
Candlestick as you guys can see right
here this literally happens everywhere
in the chart this right here is a prime
and perfect example of a bullish
engulfing Candlestick this bullish
Candlestick has engulfed this red
Candlestick in that return it headed to
the upside this bullish Candlestick
right here has engulfed the last four to
five candles sticks so obviously the
more candles that the engulfing
Candlestick eats the stronger it's the
best confirmation you can possibly ever
asked for it's like if you were to throw
a bait into the ocean and you were to
have five six fish about to bite it it's
great signal that you're about to catch
a fish so is a great signal that this
trade is about to continue going in the
direction that the Candlestick has
engulfed make sure you guys remember
that so this is going to be a bullish
engulfing Candlestick this right here
here is a perfect example of a bearish
engulfing Candlestick this Candlestick
clearly has engulfed this blue
Candlestick in return it then heads to
the upside and I can go on examples for
this for literally hours because every
single Candlestick engulfs for the
majority of the time as you can see
right here this Candlestick right here
has clearly engulfed the last 1 2 3 4 5
6 seven canister
that should be a really good indication
that this trade is now then going to
head to the upside and clearly it did
Now does not happen that there's usually
more bullish engulfing candlesticks or
more bearish engulfing candlesticks that
is a complete myth it is literally a
facade if the market is heading to the
upside you're probably going to have
more bullish Eng engulfing candlesticks
obviously if the Market's heading to the
downside you're going to obviously have
more bearish engulfing candlesticks
bullish engulfing is not strong than
bearish engulfing bearish engulfing is
not stronger than bullish engulfing they
both have the same equal effect the only
thing that matters is what is the trend
doing the trend is going up you want a
bullish engulfing if the be if the trend
is going down you want a bearish
engulfing cister so now you are
officially in your position you have
your entry signal and you have
officially entered the trade well what
now right like what what the [__] do you
do now well what do you do after you
catch a fish well you you know you reing
man or if you have an automatic Rod you
just click the button reels it in well
this is kind of what you would do in
trading you would literally just click
on buy the trade sell the trade and you
set and forget you wait for your trade
to hit your takeprofit or for it to hit
your stop loss once you catch one of
these big fishes simply click on the rod
so it reels it in for you and you just
wait for it to hit the top of the boat
you grab it put it in do it again or you
wait for the line to snap or for the
fish to get off the hook it happens
there's nothing you can do about about
it it is absolutely inevitable it is the
same exact thing in trading if you lose
a position there's nothing you can do
about it it is absolutely inevitable you
can learn from that loss and you can see
if you did something wrong and then use
that to your advantage for then the next
trade cuz if you did something wrong you
fix it you don't do it again but if you
did nothing wrong you simply just take
another trade it's going to happen
you're going to lose trades as part of
the market if you just lost a fish you
have to see if the line was too light if
your Hook was too small if the fish was
too big you analyze that you fix it you
do it again doesn't happen but sometimes
the line might break sometimes a hook
might come off there's nothing you can
do it is inevitable that you're not
going to stop yourself from fishing if
you just lost a fish if anything that's
going to give you more of a reason to
stay there and catch another big fish
it's going to make you more patient and
when you catch that fish it's more
successful it's more rewarding the same
exact thing in trading you lose a trade
you don't quit you just don't you know
leave you wait for the next let get a
trade take that same trade back make
your losses back and then you're
profitable and if at this point if
you've learned fishing hit the Subscribe
button cuz then this might turn into a
[__] fishing channel so hit the
Subscribe button so after you've done
that this is pretty much everything you
would need in order to become a swing
Trader obviously this is all very entry
level and it pretty much sums up of you
only having to take one to two positions
a week max if you don't take any trades
throughout the week trust me that is
totally fine I've gone two to three
weeks with without taking any trades but
after that happens I get a really really
big winner after that because I've been
waiting for a very solid trade setup you
want to make sure that you are taking
trades on lowrisk pairs on pairs that
don't move that much that don't have a
lot of volatility so you can take a high
percentage risk on your accounts that
way you can actually make more money
than a day trader than a scalper than
any of these other wannabe Traders
honestly I personally love the fact that
I'm a swing Trader obviously you can
tell tell I am the CEO of Swing trading
lab one of the top educational companies
in the world where we let Traders make
anywhere from ,000 to $1,500 a week as a
beginner set and forget Trader and if
you don't know what set and forget is
well it is literally the creation of the
best swing trading strategy out there in
the market let's Traders make profits
like these or even these and if you
don't know what s and forget is just hit
the link in the description below
there's a video there for you that
explains to you exact exactly what set
and fra is and what it is consisted of
and how it's let Traders make anywhere
from ,000 to $11,500 a week as a
beginner set foret Trader and it's not
just videos it's I literally get on a
call with you every single week where I
share with you my top two top three or
even top four pairs that I trade for the
week so you can have the same results
that I do picture it as if we were to go
fishing together every single week and
I'm going to share with you the best
spots that you can go and fish at the
odds of you catching fish fish are going
to be a lot higher than not well it's
exact same thing in the markets we're
going to be taking the same traits
together on the weekends so you can have
the best odds of making money rather
than not it's not like all these other
guys that just give you videos and they
say peace out no we're together every
single weekend so I can show you what
set and forget is about so if you want
to know more about set and forget and
how it works make sure you hit the link
in the description below and I'll see
you guys inside and thank you guys for
watching the video all the way to the
end I'll see you guys in the next video